CONOR STUART-ROE

+1.828.785.0136 • conorstuartroe@yahoo.com

ticha.haverford.edu • www.linkedin.com/in/conorstuartroe/ • www.conorstuartroe.com

natural languages: English native • Mandarin HSK4 • Dutch B1

computer languages: Python • Java • JS/jQuery • HTML • CSS/Bootstrap • PHP • various XML (TEI, XSLT, SSML) other technologies: NLTK • NumPy • pandas • DigitalOcean • Heroku • Django • TensorFlow • Git • Excel

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Python Development

I have very extensive professional experience with Python, using it to build backend web architecture, corpus management software, and artificial intelligence algorithms. I am closely familiar with NLP and analysis libraries such as NumPy, pandas, TensorFlow, and NLTK.

Mathematical Modeling and Deep Learning

A firm grounding in linear algebra, statistics, and discrete math, and practical experience using it in applications such as latent semantic analysis, principal component analysis, entropy modeling, language modeling, RSA encryption, and neural network architecture.

Natural Language Analysis and Processing

I have award-winning technical skills in formal linguistic analysis, and experience applying in contexts as diverse as descriptive linguistics research, corpus management, and deep learning language modeling.

Full Stack Web Development

I have built websites from both a higher level through WordPress as well as backend architecture with Django, AWS, DigitalOcean, Heroku, SQLite.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Develo	per for Ticha at Ha	everford Digital	Scholarship
I all stack bevelo	per ior riena atric	averiora Digitat	Scholarship

Philadelphia, PA

Jan 2017-present

Ticha is an online dictionary and primary source database for the Zapotec language, built with Django on a Droplet. In collaboration with student researchers, I've built new features such as TEI parsers, reader interfaces, and automated PDF generation, using a combination of Python and front-end web tools.

Artificial Intelligence Developer at Ivy.ai

Durham, NC

Jun-Aug 2017

For Ivy's chatbot service, I conducted research and testing of natural language understanding software capable of reading the web to build a semi-unstructured ontology and answer questions from students and other university website visitors. I also created a new company site from scratch in three weeks with WordPress.

Feature Writer and Quantitative Analytics Developer at Dynalect Analytics

Jan-Jul 2017

For a finance blog that I co-created, I built a professional and responsive site with WordPress, wrote weekly pieces and monthly long-form industry analyses, and created predictive machine learning models of financial markets.

Creator and teacher of three linguistics seminars at NCSSM Teaching Assistant for Mandarin and mathematics at NCSSM Durham, NC

2014-2015

EDUCATION

Haverford College, B.S. & B.A.

Philadelphia, PA

2016-2020

GPA: 3.95

degrees in progress: Linguistics, Computer Science

North Carolina School of Science and Mathematics, high school

Durham, NC

2013-2015

Weighted GPA: 5.37 Composite SAT: 2390

AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS

Silver Medalist, International Olympiad in Linguistics

Blagoevgrad, Bulgaria Jul 2015

I performed second among over 3000 North American competitors to qualify. My team received first prize at IOL.